<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Elaine</title>
    <description>I am a university student and front-end designer. I love contributing to global greenhouse gas emissions by constantly spewing opinions. This is my blog.</description>
    <link>http://elaineg.github.io/blog/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://elaineg.github.io/blog/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 10:07:43 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 10:07:43 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>I told 8 year olds how to do drugs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“What’s crack cocaine?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were on a train and one of the little girls in my field trip group had spotted somebody smoking a cigarette a few seats away. Obviously, it had jogged her memory and brought a passing subject she’d heard to light. At the time, I was their temporary legal guardian and I was told to be a responsible adult. I had my tongue primed give the typical responsible adult answer: “You’ll know when you’re older”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew they’d despise that answer, just as I did when I was young. But it’s common sense that they can’t get themselves into trouble if they don’t know about something, right? If we don’t teach them, it simply won’t be a part of their world, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Crack cocaine is a drug! But not a medicine type of drug, it’s more like cigarettes. It’s pretty bad for you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How do you take it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, you can smoke it just like you smoke cigarettes. You roll it into a tube, light it on fire, and then you breathe in the smoke. Another way is by breathing it through your nose.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People say it can get to your brain faster that way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large, burly man was squinting me down from across the narrow floor. Sitting beside him, a mother rocking her baby, month agape. I pretended not to notice them and soldiered on. I was having way too much fun imparting all the information I had ever learned about drugs to stop now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But why do people do it if it’s not good for them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, they get addicted. They don’t really know why, but they can’t stop using it and they always want more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m addicted to the TV,” Another young boy, eavesdropping a little ways away had picked up on our conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I guess it’s kind of like that. You keep on wanting to watch more, even if it might not be good for you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I probably didn’t get any society points for being a good babysitter that day as I was getting pretty murderous looks from passing strangers, but I was ecstatic. I’ve always been terrible with children because I never put the effort in to connect with them, but today, we reached an understanding through hard drugs. Today, I was lead to believe that innocent curiosity exists, free of malicious intent, and that children deserve a straight answer given with respect. It’s the only way I got them to respect me in return.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://elaineg.github.io/blog/blog/blog/kids-and-drugs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://elaineg.github.io/blog/blog/blog/kids-and-drugs</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A hundred 'Hello World!'s and counting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s another one. Hello, World!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I finally join the leagues of infant bloggers that have successfully figured out how to beam their computer hacker messages onto the internet after a dizzying number of attempts. My head feels light, but I’m sure this is entirely due to the alarming amount of hair I’ve lost out of frustration. I’ve put this blog here to hopefully convince my mom that I am capable of doing things with my time despite my front of lying on a couch mindlessly consuming trashy media and to write to undemanding, imaginary friends instead of opening my anxiety-inducing inboxes. It’s a perfect solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve been building this site, I’ve picked up on some bits of internet culture that remind me why so many flock to the extremely left-wing bubble society that is the internet to escape from real life. Once upon a time several years ago, I myself was an informed netizen and Tumblr memes were my religion. I gradually drifted from the clique, however, when I forgot my password. At the time, there were concepts that my young age prevented me from understanding so I thought people memed on Mitt Romney during his election cycle purely because he dropped a chicken wing at a barbecue one time. I see now the more pc reason for all the flak he got was because he was the current figurehead of capitalist values. He was the purveyor of the “irl” mentality that in order to be successful, you have to get paid for your work. That logic makes sense because humans need to eat to live, but like all the other rules it doesn’t seem to apply to the internet. Here, it’s the accepted norm to create things that people can use for free. Brilliant, busy people with lives to live instead dedicate their hours to make tools for others to use, and that’s why we have Wikipedia and Kim Kardashian. Essentially, I want to thank all the smart samaritans that live on the internet forums where I copied all the complicated computer things needed to say hello to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://elaineg.github.io/blog/blog/blog/hello-worlds</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://elaineg.github.io/blog/blog/blog/hello-worlds</guid>
        
        
        <category>thoughts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
