<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Elaine Gao</title>
    <description>I am a front-end web and layout designer. This is my blog.</description>
    <link>http://elainegao.com/blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://elainegao.com/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 12:35:18 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 12:35:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>Non-corporate sets make for better sitcoms</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.postgradproblems.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/09/74e3f3b99d685b83e99ad9cfab0458c4.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Office vs Parks and Recreation&quot; title=&quot;Both main characters play at being lovable, but it doesn't help if you're generally an asshole.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American sitcom &lt;em&gt;Parks and Recreation&lt;/em&gt; is miles ahead of its predecessor, &lt;em&gt;The Office&lt;/em&gt;. It didn’t revolve around a single social cripple, its supporting characters were everything you wished your squad could be, and “treat yo’ self” is the most applicable line that has ever come from the small screen. On the surface, it’s easy to put it down to talented show-runner(s) refining their craft for a new masterpiece, but after trying out The Office for two seasons, I promptly re binge-watched all seven seasons of Parks and Recreation. This time, I reached a deeper conclusion. Sort of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parks and Recreation’s taxpayer funded atmosphere made for more enjoyable TV. It allowed for more character development and more highly anticipated detail into their personal lives. The situation felt more probable, which led to the mood being more genuine than the awkward uneasiness that plagued The Office. You cannot tell me that Angela Kinsley was okay with having an illicit affair with Dwight Shrute. You can’t. Maybe that’s the point in the name of absurdist humor, but nobody enjoys thinking about it in detail. In fact, I’m sorry I brought the image to your mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inane and inconsequential Parks and Recreation department brought no attention to the employees’ skills and roles in the department, instead focusing on their odd idiosyncrasies and personalities. In fact, you get the feeling this is a real life island of misfit toys. What the heck is Jerry doing there, but to be Terry? This is a huge contrast to the corporate world where each hire and each process is streamlined because they’re here to make as much profit as possible while spending the least amount of money they can get away with. Everyone has to have a role. In The Office, each cast member didn’t just have a role, but they had a personality that supported it instead of the other way around. Uptight Angela Martin was the very definition of micromanaging accountant. Toby’s human resources position was ironic because he was so poor at social interactions. Chill, charismatic dudes Jim and Ryan were sales hustlers, while plain Pam was the perfect receptionist. The best remembered characters were the ones that had personalities that transcended their jobs and made you forget that they were supposed to be there doing actual work. Bureaucratic bloat and unproductivity was a recurring theme in both shows, and it’s easy to see where it felt more at home. In both shows, characters were displaying incredible talent at doing their jobs poorly. For The Office, I’d constantly wonder why Michael Scott couldn’t be fired. For Parks, I forgot Donna was working a job. By no means does Parks depict real life any better than The Office, but while I was watching, it just &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; more probable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because you forgot they were working a job, the show could go deeper into their personal lives without the fear of straying too far from the main premise. The Office pretty much stayed exactly within its title for the entire show, which was a shame, because arguably the most acclaimed plot line was Jim and Pam’s office turned personal relationship. I’m sure the point was to turn the office into a makeshift petri dish so audiences could see what grew specifically within those walls, but &lt;em&gt;Parks&lt;/em&gt; didn’t have these walls to be confined by. The show went behind the scenes with everybody, which forged a stronger connection between the characters and the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without these boundaries, Parks also demonstrated a much better understanding of absurdist humor, or at least the enjoyable type. At its best, absurdist humor is a great comedy medium because it is generally unoffensive, harmless, and squeaky clean. Tom Haverford’s obvious tough luck with women, his clueless obsession with glitz and glamour, his stint with Entertainment 720, and not to mention his flamboyant demeanor makes him a champion for the absurdist humor cause. On top of that, he’s just one of the many winning characters from Parks that do the same. Michael Scott and Dwight Shrute were undoubtedly written for a similar fate, but only the latter can claim to be absurd yet enjoyable. Michael Scott berates, insults, and at the very least overpowers every other cast member, but his cluelessness is not enough to make it fun to watch. He always comes out on top of a sticky situation, often without learning the right lesson. Maybe one could argue that his situation is more realistic, but it is difficult to watch Phylis’s face tremble when he unapologetically calls her handmade Christmas gift “stupid”. Angela and Dwight are a little &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; absurd for comfort. It’s too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corporate settings can make extremely entertaining television. &lt;em&gt;Suits&lt;/em&gt;, with its high intensity storyline and overzealous drama is an excellent example. It focuses on one place where corporate jobs excel: Lots of pressure, bringing high stakes along for the ride. The specific flavour of chill situational comedy brought to life by Michael Schur and friends best showcases the exact opposite. While the premise of a show set at a paper company in a world that is actively trying to use less paper is hilarious, it ultimately cannot compete with a set where ineffective bureaucracy is at the core of its existence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://elainegao.com/blog/nonprofit-vs-corporate</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://elainegao.com/blog/nonprofit-vs-corporate</guid>
        
        <category>film and tv</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Parent picks: Taken with Niam Leeson</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Movies can be academic. At least, that’s the lie I tell myself in order to justify living a life completely composed of oxygen consumption. On the bright side, I live in an ideal set of circumstances to become a movie scholar. The movie preferences of my family members are perfect clichés. My dad keeps himself sane on unspeakably awful Asian warrior soaps and mindless spy films, while my mother only watches BBC’s most critically acclaimed rom coms (“My time is too precious!”). My tasteless self leans more toward the trash action genre, but I recently got baited to attend a surprise birthday on the premise we would be baking Jane Austen pastries. Actions speak louder than words, so while my dignity can’t admit to having an affinity for chick flicks, I know I’m certainly not kidding anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I constantly make fun of both my parents for their taste in movies to smother my own preference insecurities, but I’m always around to watch what they have on. Today, my dad was feeling uncharacteristically social and for the first time I can remember, he invited me to watch a movie with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so down, I forgot to ask what he was planning to put on. In retrospect, that probably would have made no difference anyway. I would’ve just said “Anything’s fine!” but turn my nose up at any concrete choice presented. Besides, the opening credits were long over before I could string a coherent thought together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next 99 minutes I watched a movie that was incredibly unoffensive given its subject matter about forcing a kidnapped girl into sex trafficking. But&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.military.com/media/offduty/movies/taken2phone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A portrait of Niam Leeson&quot; title=&quot;Good man saves more than just his daughter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team of brilliant people got together and tried to sell me the notion that this man is a hero that saves baby children, and I gotta say: they went above and beyond. He did more than save his kid: He is the savior of this movie. Niam Leeson, whose name looks like exactly the same thing if you reverse the first letters and spell Liam Neeson. Wait, which one IS it? You don’t know anymore. Anyway, he kicked butt so hard it grew up and became a trilogy of films. The &lt;em&gt;Taken&lt;/em&gt; franchise appears to be the equivalent of Apple product releases: The exact same thing is released every year with a few minor tweaks. In &lt;em&gt;Taken 2&lt;/em&gt;, the same kid is stolen, but there’s the gripping twist where his ex-wife gets stolen too. It’s an extremely inconsequential storyline, to the point where I cannot even remember the main character’s name. Only Niam Leeson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TL;DR: I feel bad if I call this movie trash one more time because Leeson looked extremely sad the entire movie. I am now obliged to say it was a solid dad pick. At the very least, it’s a marked improvement over his old Chinese soaps because people have guns, which are handy catalysts to improve a sluggish, stale plot line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://elainegao.com/blog/taken-with-niam-leeson</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://elainegao.com/blog/taken-with-niam-leeson</guid>
        
        <category>film and tv</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I taught 8 year olds how to do drugs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“What’s crack cocaine?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were on a train and one of the little girls in my field trip group had spotted somebody smoking a cigarette a few seats away. Obviously, it had jogged her memory and brought a passing subject she’d heard to light. At the time, I was their temporary legal guardian and I was told to be a responsible adult. I had my tongue primed give the typical responsible adult answer: “You’ll know when you’re older”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew they’d despise that answer, just as I did when I was young. But it’s common sense that they can’t get themselves into trouble if they don’t know about something, right? If we don’t teach them, it simply won’t be a part of their world, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Crack cocaine is a drug! But not a medicine type of drug, it’s more like cigarettes. It’s pretty bad for you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How do you take it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, you can smoke it just like you smoke cigarettes. You roll it into a tube, light it on fire, and then you breathe in the smoke. Another way is by breathing it through your nose.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Why?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“People say it can get to your brain faster that way.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large, burly man was squinting me down from across the narrow floor. Sitting beside him, a mother rocking her baby, mouth agape. I pretended not to notice them and soldiered on. I was having way too much fun imparting all the information I had ever learned about drugs to stop now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“But why do people do it if it’s not good for them?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Well, they get addicted. They don’t really know why, but they can’t stop using it and they always want more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I’m addicted to the TV,” Another young boy, eavesdropping a little ways away had picked up on our conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I guess it’s kind of like that. You keep on wanting to watch more, even if it might not be good for you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I probably didn’t get any society points for being a good babysitter that day as I was getting pretty murderous looks from passing strangers, but I was ecstatic. I’ve always been terrible with children because I never put the effort in to connect with them, but today, we reached an understanding through hard drugs. Today, I was lead to believe that innocent curiosity exists, free of malicious intent, and that children deserve a straight answer given with respect. It’s the only way I got them to respect me in return.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://elainegao.com/blog/kids-and-drugs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://elainegao.com/blog/kids-and-drugs</guid>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A hundred 'Hello World!'s and counting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s another one. Hello, World!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, I finally join the leagues of infant bloggers that have successfully figured out how to beam their computer hacker messages onto the internet after a dizzying number of attempts. My head feels light, but I’m sure this is entirely due to the alarming amount of hair I’ve lost out of frustration. I’ve put this blog here to hopefully convince my mom that I am capable of doing things with my time despite my front of lying on a couch mindlessly consuming trashy media and to write to undemanding, imaginary friends instead of opening my anxiety-inducing inboxes. It’s a perfect solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve been building this site, I’ve picked up on some bits of internet culture that remind me why so many flock to the extremely left-wing bubble society that is the internet to escape from real life. Once upon a time several years ago, I myself was an informed netizen and Tumblr memes were my religion. I gradually drifted from the clique, however, when I forgot my password. At the time, there were concepts that my young age prevented me from understanding so I thought people memed on Mitt Romney during his election cycle purely because he dropped a chicken wing at a barbecue one time. I see now the more pc reason for all the flak he got was because he was the current figurehead of capitalist values. He was the purveyor of the “irl” mentality that in order to be successful, you have to get paid for your work. That logic makes sense because humans need to eat to live, but like all the other rules it doesn’t seem to apply to the internet. Here, it’s the accepted norm to create things that people can use for free. Brilliant, busy people with lives to live instead dedicate their hours to make tools for others to use, and that’s why we have Wikipedia and Kim Kardashian. Essentially, I want to thank all the smart samaritans that live on the internet forums where I copied all the complicated computer things needed to say hello to the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://elainegao.com/blog/hello-worlds</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://elainegao.com/blog/hello-worlds</guid>
        
        <category>web development</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
